<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>erikg</author>
  <title>Which Code School is the Best?</title>
  <description>Which Code School is the best?&amp;nbsp;As the owners of a programming boot camp and people with years o</description>
  <content>&lt;p&gt;Which Code School is the best?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the owners of a programming boot camp and people with years of experience in technology, we have heard these questions [more] a few times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, there is no such thing as the best programming boot camp.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is such a thing as the best programming boot camp for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technically, there are thousands of programming languages. There is no school on Earth that teaches all of them, much less 10% of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, there are hundreds of teaching methodologies and learning practices in existence. Meaning, each school has their own methods of instructing and teaching. Some schools teach by live instruction, some pair students up, some allow students to individually move through content at their own pace, some are fully online, some combine more than one of these methodologies, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the first question is: What are you interested in learning and how are you interested in learning it?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After figuring that out, one should thoroughly review the school’s curriculum and teaching methods. Are they covering the areas you want to know? Can you commit to the required schedule or do you need flexible hours? Are you able to attend at their location or do you need the option to access the curriculum online?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look over what they offer and see if it interests you. Discover if you can meet their basic demands of a student.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another useful tool is to figure out what industry or profession you’d like to work in. For example: Do you want to develop game apps for iPhone and iPad? Do you want to be a software developer for a major company? Are you only looking to make web sites? Answering these questions can help a lot in determining the best code school for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any programming boot camp or code school professing to be "the best" should set off a red flag within you instantly. As with any subject, how could there be a best? There could be a “best in my opinion”. For example: What’s the best food? Best restaurant? Best song? Best music? Best day of the year? And so on. It all depends on who you’re asking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, again, the real question is “What is the best programming boot camp for me?” Just as you would choose a house, you should choose your code school. Shop around, educate yourself, and pick. There will be pros and cons to each.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Luckily there are so many online resources nowadays that even if your school doesn’t cover everything you wanted, you can self-train afterwards. The better schools out there will put some emphasis on teaching you not just the tools and methodologies of coding, but how to think like a software developer. This has many benefits, not the least of which is that it will make it much easier for you to rapidly come up to speed in a new language or development tool later in your career.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a final note, we recommend you take into account the people you interact with at various boot camps as you do your research. Are they friendly and helpful? Do you feel like you would enjoy having them run you through a sometimes rigorous training program? It does matter how well you get along with the people you'll work with to break into the technology industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We hope this assists you in your search, and that you have a long and successful career. If you have any additional questions, feel free to email us at info@learncodinganywhere.com.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Written by Jack Stanley and Erik Gross, Founders of The Tech Academy - www.learncodinganywhere.com&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tech Academy is a code school that runs a 15 week programming boot camp, called the Software Developer Boot Camp. Students learn front and backend web development, and almost ten computer programming languages. It is a comprehensive program with 100% placement rate of graduates.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-09-24 13:39:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-09-24 20:42:08</lastModified>
  <raters>1</raters>
  <rating>5</rating>
  <slug>which-code-school-is-the-best</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>