<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>jacks</author>
  <title>Disney</title>
  <description>​What I got out of doing&amp;nbsp;​The ​Tech Academy - by Jason Clements [more]​The Tech Academy has cha</description>
  <content>&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​What I got out of doing&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​The ​&lt;/div&gt;Tech Academy - by Jason Clements [more]&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p style="line-height: 1;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1;"&gt;​The T&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1;"&gt;ech Academy has changed my life and I want to let people know where I was before I started and what I accomplished with it in such a short time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;To start, I have never been in tech, I had absolutely no experience with programming. The only thing that I had ever done that even had a flavor of it was some advanced Excel work. I had been in sales my entire life. I was great at it but like most sales people I found that I was working really long hours, at times had to travel and be away from my family, and had deal with the weeks where I just didn't sell much and had to experience the painful side of a primarily commissioned based income.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;About two years ago when my wife and I found out that we were going to have a second child (already had a 3 year old at that point) I knew I would have to change something career wise so that I could be with my family more and honestly get out of working j&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​​&lt;/div&gt;ust for sake of working.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I didn’t know what to do at first so I started driving for Uber and Lyft which provided a lot of work flexibility and I could make decent money with it in San Francisco. After a year of doing it I had the opportunity of talking to thousands of people about their lives and careers and there was one thing that completely stood out to me: it was the programmers that were the happiest people I met and had the most financial security and even above that were able to do the things they wanted to do in their life.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I got really interested in a programming career so I started to ask people what the best way was to get started. Driving in SF actually gave me the opportunity to talk to programmers, recruiters, HR managers, and even several executives and a couple CEOs of major tech companies about how to get started. Literally, every single one of them told me the same thing: the number one place they want to get their programmers from is from a software bootcamp school.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I did A LOT of research into different bootcamps. They all seemed great but there were a few things that really made Tech Academy stand out to me:&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;1. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The curriculum seemed well balanced covering both front and back end development. Most of the bootcamps that I researched would only teach either front end or back end (not both) and usually taught only one language.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;2. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; After talking with Tech Academy themselves I saw that the team there worked to provide a certain amount of flexibility to their students so that people who had families and still had to work had options to still get through the school.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;3. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; And probably the most important thing to me was that they were the ONLY tech school that actually provided courses that could take someone from having no experience or education in programming to a well-trained programmer in a short amount of time. NONE of the other bootcamps (even if they said they did) could bring on and teach students from scratch. They all required a certain amount of experience and knowledge in the field first.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;At the time I found&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​The ​&lt;/div&gt;Tech Academy I had some commitments that would occupy most of my time for several months that I really could not get out of. But I knew it was the right decision so I did sign up immediately knowing I wouldn’t be able to start until later.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I finally got started about two months ago and I will tell you that these last two months have been a major rocket ride in my life. Right from the start with the Computer Basics Course I was learning more than I thought I could ever know about tech, computers, and programming. I want to make this very clear:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE COMPUTER BASICS COURSE ALONE MAKES ANY AMOUNT OF MONEY YOU PAY FOR&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​THE ​&lt;/div&gt;TECH ACADEMY MORE THAN WORTH IT. NO ONE ELSE HAS ANYTHING REMOTELY CLOSE TO THE EDUCATION IN THIS COURSE AND IT WILL GIVE YOU THE FOUNDATION THAT YOU NEED TO ENSURE MAXIMUM SUCCESS IN THE TECH INDUSTRY. I AM CONVINCED THAT ANY FAILURE OR HARDSHIP SOMEONE HAS IN DOING TECH IS SOLELY BECAUSE THEY DO NOT HAVE THE EDUCATION THAT IS IN THIS COURSE.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I was spending every spare moment I had doing&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​The ​&lt;/div&gt;Tech Academy. I was doing most of it online and also worked out my schedule so that I could go in person to Tech Academy for 2 weeks to do it even more intensively in that time. The instructors were all amazing and totally willing and able to help me with anything.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;It really stuck out to me how focused and caring all of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​The ​&lt;/div&gt;Tech Academy staff were on ensuring that I had success. Most educational systems I have been in since I was a child were set up to just throw a bunch of information about random subjects at me and then when that class or semester was over I was on my own. Not here; the staff all have as their primary goal to have every single one of their students succeed in the industry and that is the product that they are all personally going after.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;A good analogy is that&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​T&lt;/div&gt;he Tech Academy instructors help you in a way as if they were bridge-building teachers that would one day have to cross the bridges that their students built in order to make it home. If you had to cross a bridge that one of your students built then you know that you are going to damn well ensure your students are VERY successful bridge builders.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;After just 4 weeks into the curriculum I began telling everybody that I was going to a tech school and any tech person I met or would run into I would tell them what I was learning. At the time, I wasn’t even sure what exactly I wanted to do or where I wanted to work at but I was hungry for connections in the industry and figured the more connections I had and the more people that knew about me would come in handy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;In the process of doing this I ran into a guy that worked for Disney Studios. As soon as I found out that he worked there my interest piqued. I have always loved the film industry and even started my high school’s first film club. And I am a big comic book geek and Disney recently bought Marvel. I thought that that would be a perfect place to work. I also thought that it was pie in the sky that I could work there after coding for just a few weeks. But I said to hell with those considerations it doesn't hurt to give it a shot.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I got the guy to give me his boss’s contact information and through some polite persistence I got the boss to agree to give a phone interview. Then&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​T&lt;/div&gt;he Tech Academy instructors on a daily basis started to prep me for the interview and what to do in the hiring process. This was awesomely extensive and gave me the confidence I needed to do the interview. After a 30 minute phone interview I was invited to Disney Studios to do an in-person interview.&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​The ​&lt;/div&gt;Tech Academy prepped me for that one too. I was able to handle all the questions including the technical ones and felt good about the interview.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I am now very excited to say that after just doing about 2 months at&amp;nbsp;&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="display: inline;"&gt;​The ​&lt;/div&gt;Tech Academy I was just hired by Walt Disney Studios as a front end developer for $145,600 a year! This is a literal dream job for me and I will have enough income to support my family and work on accomplishing other goals I have.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I know this success story is already long, but I cannot stress enough how important it is to do Tech Academy and this education and support. If you want to change your life and if you want to become a major part of what is one of the top industries in the world then commit yourself to getting through your courses and then really apply the education and skills you are getting (like anything, you are only going to get back what you get into action on). And if you are not yet a student of Tech Academy then become one now, it’s that simple.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you to everyone at Tech Academy for your amazing approach at teaching me and your stellar support and care in ensuring my success!&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-10-20 10:56:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-10-20 18:05:52</lastModified>
  <raters>2</raters>
  <rating>4.5</rating>
  <slug>disney</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments>
    <comment id="5b158525-e196-4ffa-bd3a-847c96967479" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="False" spam="False" deleted="False">
      <date>2015-10-20 20:26:04</date>
      <author>Cody Landry</author>
      <email>cody.landry@icloud.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>168.215.114.98</ip>
      <avatar />
      <content>Wow, that&amp;#39;s amazing. Congratulations. Great job. You deserve it. </content>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>