<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>jacks</author>
  <title>What is a Code School?</title>
  <description>You may or may
not have heard of “code schools” or “coding boot camps”. What are they? [more]Coding:</description>
  <content>&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;You may or may
not have heard of “code schools” or “coding boot camps”. What are they? [more]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Coding:&lt;/b&gt; (noun) The act of writing or revising a computer program.
From Latin &lt;i&gt;codex&lt;/i&gt;, meaning “book”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;Coding is also referred
to as “software development” or “programming”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Boot camp:&lt;/b&gt; (noun) An intensive training program, as for improving
one's physical fitness or skills in a particular subject area. “Boot” comes from
Middle English &lt;i&gt;bot&lt;/i&gt;, meaning “help”.
“Camp” comes from Latin &lt;i&gt;campus&lt;/i&gt;,
meaning “level ground” (specifically from the Roman usage of a level ground
utilized for games, athletic practice, and military drills).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;A coding boot
camp, also commonly called a “developer boot camp” or “programming boot camp”,
is an intensive training program in software development. There are many
developer boot camps in the world. Usually they have these characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoListParagraph" style="margin-left: 0.25in;"&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;·&lt;span style="font-stretch: normal;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!--[endif]--&gt;The programs take about 2-6 months full-time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoListParagraph" style="margin-left: 0.25in;"&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;·&lt;span style="font-stretch: normal;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!--[endif]--&gt;The technical skills taught are aimed at getting
immediate employment as a junior-level software developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoListParagraph" style="margin-left: 0.25in;"&gt;&lt;!--[if !supportLists]--&gt;·&lt;span style="font-stretch: normal;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!--[endif]--&gt;The training environment is “immersive”, meaning
that students immerse themselves in the subject – often putting other life
concerns on hold as they work through the training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;Developer boot
camps are a relatively new element of the technology education landscape – the
first boot camps began in the San Francisco Bay Area in 2012. The educational
roots of coding boot camps go back quite far, from traditional apprentice
programs to the career schools that sprung up in the early 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;The rise of dev
boot camps was driven by the shortage of technical talent faced by the
technology industry. The U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics estimates that by the
year 2020, there will be over 1 million unfilled computing jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;In response to
this shortage, the technology industry has had to look for non-traditional ways
to create the technical talent it needs. Rather than a replacement for the
traditional college path to a career in software development, coding boot camps
are just one more way to arrive at a very desirable place – employed in a
well-paying, challenging field with good job security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;Whereas colleges
are good options for those who can afford it and are able to study for 2-4
years, boot camps can be a resource for students that want to learn coding who
have less available funds and time. Both are excellent options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;There are a wide
variety of dev boot camps in the country. For those interested in taking this
path to break into the technology field, it can be daunting – often the
prospective student is unfamiliar with the very terms describing the contents
of a boot camp’s training program. It can also be difficult to make a decision
about what specific set of skills one should seek in order to have the best
shot at landing a good job. Finally, some boot camps will only work with
students who already have some programming experience or education.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;In our opinion,
here are some things worth looking into if you’re thinking of attending a
coding boot camp:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-left:.5in;text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Does the program cover the fundamentals of
Computer Science?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;The technology
field changes rapidly. Without a solid understanding of the basics of how
computers work, it can be difficult to keep up with a changing technology
landscape.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-left:.5in;text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Will you learn a variety of different
computer programming languages and systems?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;If you have a
deep but narrow skill set in only one or two technologies, you may find it
challenging to find a job outside of those technologies – and when that
language falls out of favor, you may have an uphill battle in gaining skills in
the new, more popular technologies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-left:.5in;text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Is the program self-paced?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;We all learn at
different rates. If you have to move in lock-step with other students, you may
find yourself frustrated or left behind. An ideal training program will let you
speed ahead when you are doing well, but will quickly handle any confusions or
barriers when you get stuck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="margin-left:.5in;text-align:justify"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Does the program cover soft skills?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;Soft skills are
those non-technical abilities that make a potential employee quite desirable.
These are things like good manners, effective communication, leadership skills,
the ability to cooperate in a team dynamic, and more. Even in a market with a
talent shortage, these things matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Will you work on real-world coding projects,
and not just textbook exercises?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;There is much
you can learn from a well-run classroom – but at some point, you’ve got to dive
in on a live project. There’s no substitute for proving to yourself that you
can produce a valuable, working product that’s meant to be used in the real
world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Most importantly, will the program help you
get employed?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;At the end of
the day, all that will really matter is that you are able to utilize the tools
you learned as a developer. Attending a boot camp and then living in your
parent’s basement, unemployed, would be a failure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align:justify;text-indent:.5in"&gt;We hope this
clears up what a code school is and helps you in your search for a job in the
technical field.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;











































































































&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Written by Jack
Stanley and Erik Gross, Founders of The Tech Academy. The Tech Academy is a
code school that runs a 15 week Software Developer Boot Camp that can be taken
online from anywhere, or in-person at their Portland campus. To find out more
about The Tech Academy,&amp;nbsp; visit their
website: www.learncodinganywhere.com. Learn coding. Get hired. It’s that
simple.&amp;nbsp;&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-09-17 13:34:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-09-17 20:37:30</lastModified>
  <raters>2</raters>
  <rating>3</rating>
  <slug>what-is-a-code-school</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>