<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>jacks</author>
  <title>Graduate Story - Scott Jansen</title>
  <description>​I was a full-time computer programmer (using Cobol) for six years between 1981 and 1987, but I had </description>
  <content>&lt;div class="gmail_default" style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-size: small; line-height: 1; font-family: 'trebuchet ms', sans-serif; display: inline; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"&gt;​&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style="line-height: 1;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;I was a full-time computer programmer (using Cobol) for six years between 1981 and 1987, but I had not done any programming [more] of any kind since 1990 when I enrolled in The Tech Academy in February of 2015. The general principles of programming were very familiar, but the specific implementations where entirely new to me. I had never even heard of C# or SQL prior to February.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;I researched the types of modern languages out there and their common usages and their basic structures, and came to the preliminary conclusion that I wanted to focus on C# and SQL. Then I looked for software bootcamps that seemed to engage heavily in those two areas and also that were in a geographic area that was appealing to my wife. The Tech Academy in Portland was ideal on every front--even the tuition cost was favorable relative to other similar options.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;So, I threw myself full-time into my studies. I knew that my future depended on how well I soaked up the knowledge that was being provided, so I did everything in my power to maximize everything that I absorbed. Where the subject matter was in line with my hopes for my future job, I did a lot of the optional tasks in addition to the required ones. I worked at least 50 hours per week, usually significantly more than that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;When it came time for job searching, The Tech Academy helped me in several ways: providing leads, providing coaching on the process, providing opportunities to engage in Live Projects, and, of course, providing the curriculum I needed to be prepared for my interviews. I sent out many resumes, probably eighty in all. I eventually received three excellent job offers and had a difficult time choosing among them.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;I currently work at SBI (Small Business Innovations) in East Portland using C#, SQL and Developer Express. It has been a real struggle for me to learn Developer Express and to become "up-to-speed" in my job, but I am making tremendous progress. I have continued to learn as much as my brain can absorb and my employers have been patient with me because they see my potential. I would not be in a position to demonstrate this potential if it were not for the foundation I received at The Tech Academy. I am also grateful that the Tech Academy did not always spoon feed answers to us, but rather left us to struggle to work out solutions on our own--because this is the expectation under which I operate on a daily basis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;After two months on the job, I am no longer saddled with the title of "junior programmer." I do not have a mentor. I am an independently functioning contributing member of our small development team of roughly a dozen. It has been a stressful transition because of the speed that I have been learning, but I am now feeling much more confident that I have a secure future that will last me another twenty five years if I so choose.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;br style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;- Scott Jansen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="line-height: 1;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal; font-style: italic; font-weight: bold;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="line-height: 1;"&gt;&lt;span style="color: rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: small; line-height: normal;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-10-05 12:25:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-10-05 19:27:11</lastModified>
  <raters>1</raters>
  <rating>5</rating>
  <slug>graduate-story-scott-jansen</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>