<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>jacks</author>
  <title>Martinez's Experience at The Tech Academy</title>
  <description>At the Tech Academy I learned a lot of things. I started the
Academy knowing a little about programm</description>
  <content>&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;At the Tech Academy I learned a lot of things. I started the
Academy knowing a little about programming but not much. In the beginning of
the program we learned about the computer and how it works. Even though I have
been working with computers for years I felt like this was a good refresher. It
sort of preps your brain for the vast amount of information it’s about to
absorb in a short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;I first ran into trouble with PHP and that is when I first
learned how to search for answers and work out problems I ran into. I was
seriously stuck on this section and with the help from the Instructors and
research I found a solution for the problem I was having. I worked remotely and
although at first thought it would be more difficult, I am happy I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;One of the biggest things I learned and took away from the
Tech Academy was learning how to learn a lot of information quickly and being
able to apply the information. The job I received was for a program that I
never heard of until I applied for the job. I did some tutorials and read a
little and felt comfortable going into the interview. I was offered the
position but since I was new to the program I still had a lot to learn. I was
told by my interviewer that there was a steep learning curve and I would be
expected to learn and apply the information quickly. I was not hesitant on ensuring
him that I knew without any doubt I could learn the program very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;I kinda laughed because in the back of my mind I felt like I
had been preparing myself for a situation like this. The Tech Academy is not
easy by any means, it’s tough, tiring and sometimes makes you want to throw
your laptop against a wall. With that said however, when you find a solution to
the unsolvable problem you are faced with it makes everything you are putting
yourself through worth it. After finishing the Tech Academy I have come to
realize it has prepared me for real world situations. A lot of times you are
given a problem and expected to find a working solution in a timely manner. While
going through the program it feels like I retrained my brain to do just that
and that helped prepare me for the real world of programming.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;















&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="MsoNormal"&gt;Martinez&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-10-15 12:51:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-10-15 19:51:57</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>martinez-s-experience-at-the-tech-academy</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>