<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>jacks</author>
  <title>Cole Dixon, Graduate of the Software Developer Boot Camp</title>
  <description>I have always had a voracious appetite for knowledge across a vast myriad of different subjects and </description>
  <content>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div style=""&gt;I have always had a voracious appetite for knowledge across a vast myriad of different subjects and genres.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Coding was never something that even pinged on my radar as a possible career avenue. It was not until I heard of the unique environment and learning structure at the Tech Academy [more] that I felt inclined to look into the technology field. As I researched all of the diverse code schools that the Portland area had to offer, word kept coming around about how intentionally different the Tech Academy was in its approach to teaching the fundamentals of software development.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Upon my acceptance to Tech Academy and initial introduction to the course material, I knew I had made the correct choice. Each course is beautifully developed on an incrementing scale of difficulty to fully immerse the student in possible real-world scenarios and deeply instill the vocabulary and syntax of each coding language and OOP. With a range of interests from front-end to back-end and database implementation, everything needed to be successful in the industry is covered. Having access to Erik Gross and his wide breadth of knowledge and experience is, in itself, one of the most invaluable assets the Tech Academy offers.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Working through drills and projects that are specifically designed to test your skills and creativity one gains an incredibly in-depth knowledge of each language they are working in. I had the privilege of not only being a student but also being an employee of the Tech Academy.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The team that Erik and Jack have assembled to instruct and mentor students is a cut above. They truly are the heart of the program and have an eagerness and thirst for knowledge that is demonstrated through their teachings. One of the best skills that I received from the Tech Academy came from my time as an instructor. By working closely with students and spending time debugging their code, as opposed to my own, I saw how every individual thinks and approaches problem solving differently and that no piece of code is written the same. This has opened my mind to new ways of thinking and indirect angles to find solutions to coding challenges.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;If it were not for the skills gleaned from study and participation in all of the events and lectures Tech Academy offers, I would not have earned the job I have been offered. Participating in Tech Talks, weekly Career Round Table sessions, and meet-ups is essential to understanding the layout of the tech industry and pushing through all of the doors marked pull.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;For each student that has taken this program there is a specific language that stands out to them and becomes their favourite above others. For me that was SQL and database design.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;The innumerable amount of resources that are granted to each student allowed me to pursue my interests in databases and RDBMS alongside my course studies. Being given the opportunity to work on projects with a team working under the Agile methodologies is one of the key factors in me obtaining the job that I have now.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;I would like to extend a most gracious ‘thank you’ to the staff, Adam, Tony, Kendra, Brett, and Michelle, and all of the student body, [both remote and local], for making my time at the Tech Academy full of meaningful interactions, immersive conversations, inventive challenges, and a lot of memories and knowledge that I will carry with me into my new career in Colorado.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;img src="/image.axd?picture=%2f2015%2f09%2f15914_1043121549041075_2040891169651516931_n.jpg"&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-09-15 12:46:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-09-15 20:24:21</lastModified>
  <raters>1</raters>
  <rating>5</rating>
  <slug>cole-dixon-graduate-of-the-software-developer-boot-camp</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments>
    <comment id="86666c4e-8b38-4789-85ac-8f8da85d41ee" parentid="00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000" approved="False" spam="False" deleted="True">
      <date>2015-09-17 00:23:33</date>
      <author>Erik</author>
      <email>erik.d.gross@gmail.com</email>
      <country />
      <ip>24.21.158.188</ip>
      <avatar />
      <content>We are very proud of Cole and wish him the best!</content>
    </comment>
  </comments>
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>