<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<post>
  <author>jacks</author>
  <title>Prasana just finished the Software Developer Boot Camp!</title>
  <description>I
was looking for .NET boot-camp in Portland and when came to know
about Tech Academy, the first thi</description>
  <content>&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in; orphans: 1"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman, serif"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;font color="#222222"&gt;I
was looking for .NET boot-camp in Portland and when came to know
about Tech Academy, the first thing that impressed me was 100% job
placement. I have a computer background, so I only wanted to take the
.NET course, but the software developer boot camp was like a package,
so I started from the&amp;nbsp;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;font color="#222222"&gt;computer
basics course. As I moved on to the successive courses, I realized
just how important it was to start at the basics and progress forward
through each course.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font color="#222222"&gt;The
main thing that was helpful for me was the self paced learning
curriculum and that I would be able take the course online. The
curriculum was very comprehensive and the drills were challenging
particularly the python drills which was helpful in developing my
logic. Instructors were helpful and I got immediate response/help
from them. The live project and job placement courses are definitely
highlights in the boot-camp. In the live project, I had an
opportunity to work in a real world website and was able to
contribute to the website. The job placement course helped me prepare
for the interview. The Tech Academy taught me the skills that are
necessary for my career.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in; orphans: 1"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman, serif"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;font color="#222222"&gt;I
am happy that I gained the knowledge as well as received a job. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in; orphans: 1;"&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="margin-bottom: 0in; orphans: 1;"&gt;
&lt;font color="#222222"&gt;&lt;font face="Times New Roman, serif"&gt;&lt;font size="3"&gt;I'll
take this opportunity to thank Adam, Tony and Danny and all the other
staff in Tech Academy for their support and motivation! I am now employed in technology!&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  <ispublished>True</ispublished>
  <isdeleted>False</isdeleted>
  <iscommentsenabled>True</iscommentsenabled>
  <pubDate>2015-11-06 12:14:00</pubDate>
  <lastModified>2015-11-06 20:19:03</lastModified>
  <raters>0</raters>
  <rating>0</rating>
  <slug>prasana-just-finished-the-software-developer-boot-camp</slug>
  <tags />
  <comments />
  <categories />
  <notifications />
</post>